Вотао Нао

2000 N Shoreline Blvd, Mountain View, CA 94043

Email: haobotao000@gmail.com Website: https://haobotao000.github.io/

RESEARCH INTERESTS

I am currently working on developing principled data-efficient reinforcement learning with human feed-back (RLHF) for fine-tuning large language models (LLMs) and their application in products. I am also interested in fundamental research on reinforcement learning and multi-armed bandits.

EDUCATIONS

Ph.D. in Statistics Sep. 2014 - Dec. 2019

Department of Statistics, Purdue University

Advisor: Prof. Guang Cheng

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCES

▲ Senior Research Scientist, Deepmind, Mountain View	Feb. 2022 - Present
▲ Research Scientist, Deepmind, London	Nov. 2020 - Feb. 2022
▲ Postdoctoral Researcher, Princeton University	Dec. 2019 - Nov. 2020
Advisor: Prof. Mengdi Wang	
▲ Research Intern, Deepmind, London	May 2019 - Sep. 2019
▲ Research Intern, Adobe Research	May 2018 - Aug. 2018

JOURNAL PUBLICATIONS

▲ Sparse Tensor Additive Regression

Botao Hao, Boxiang Wang, Pengyuan Wang, Emma Jingfei Zhang, Jian Yang, Will Wei Sun *Journal of Machine Learning Research (2021)*. [ArXiv]

- ▲ Sparse and Low-rank Tensor Estimation via Cubic Sketchings Botao Hao, Anru Zhang, and Guang Cheng IEEE Transactions on Information Theory (2020). [ArXiv]
- ▲ Nonparametric Bayesian Aggregation for Massive Data Zuofeng Shang, Botao Hao, and Guang Cheng Journal of Machine Learning Research (2019). [ArXiv]
- ▲ Simultaneous Clustering and Estimation of Heterogeneous Graphical Models Botao Hao, Will Wei Sun, Yufeng Liu, and Guang Cheng Journal of Machine Learning Research (2018). [ArXiv]

CONFERENCE PUBLICATIONS

- ▲ Leveraging Demonstrations to Improve Online Learning: Quality Matters Botao Hao, Rahul Jain, Tor Lattimore, Benjamin Van Roy, Zheng Wen *ICML 2023*. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Regret Bounds for Information-Directed Reinforcement Learning Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore NeurIPS 2022. [ArXiv]
- ▲ The Neural Testbed: Evaluating Predictive Distributions
 Ian Osband, Zheng Wen, Mohamammad Asghari, Vikranth Dwaracherla, **Botao Hao**,
 Morteza Ibrahimi, Dieterich Lawson, Xiuyuan Lu, Brendan O'Donoghue, Benjamin Van Roy
 NeurIPS 2022. [ArXiv][GitHub]

- ▲ Contextual Information-Directed Sampling Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore, Chao Qin *ICML 2022.* [ArXiv]
- ▲ Interacting Contour Stochastic Gradient Langevin Dynamics Wei Deng, Siqi Liang, Botao Hao, Guang Lin, Faming Liang *ICLR 2022*. [OpenReview]
- ▲ Confident Least Square Value Iteration with Local Access to a Simulator Botao Hao, Nevena Lazic, Dong Yin, Yasin Abbasi-Yadkori, Csaba Szepesvári AISTATS 2022. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Efficient Local Planning with Linear Function Approximation Dong Yin, **Botao Hao**, Yasin Abbasi-Yadkori, Nevena Lazic, Csaba Szepesvári *ALT 2022*. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Bandit Phase Retrieval Tor Lattimore, Botao Hao NeurIPS 2021. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Information Directed Sampling for Sparse Linear Bandits Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore, Wei Deng NeurIPS 2021 (spotlight). [ArXiv]
- ▲ Bootstrapping Statistical Inference for Off-Policy Evaluation Botao Hao, Xiang Ji, Yaqi Duan, Hao Lu, Csaba Szepesvári, Mengdi Wang *ICML 2021*. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Sparse Feature Selection Makes Batch Reinforcement Learning More Sample Efficient Botao Hao, Yaqi Duan, Tor Lattimore, Csaba Szepesvári, Mengdi Wang *ICML 2021*. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Online Sparse Reinforcement Learning
 Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore, Csaba Szepesvári, Mengdi Wang
 AISTATS 2021. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Adaptive Approximate Policy Iteration

 Botao Hao, Nevena Lazic, Yasin Abbasi-Yadkori, Pooria Joulani, Csaba Szepesvári

 AISTATS 2021. [ArXiv]
- ▲ High-Dimensional Sparse Linear Bandits Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore, Mengdi Wang NeurIPS 2020. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Adaptive Exploration in Linear Contextual Bandit Botao Hao, Tor Lattimore, and Csaba Szepesvári *AISTATS 2020.* [ArXiv]
- ▲ Sparse and Low-rank Tensor Estimation via Cubic Sketchings Botao Hao, Anru Zhang, and Guang Cheng AISTATS 2020. [Link]
- ▲ Bootstrapped Upper Confidence Bound Botao Hao, Yasin Abbasi-Yadkori, Zheng Wen, and Guang Cheng NeurIPS 2019. [ArXiv]

BOOK CHAPTERS

▲ Tensors in Modern Statistical Learning
Will Wei Sun, Botao Hao, Lexin Li
In Wiley StatsRef: Statistics Reference Online. [Link]

PREPRINTS

- ▲ Sequential Best-Arm Identification with Application to Brain-Computer Interface Xin Zhou, Botao Hao, Jian Kang, Tor Lattimore, Lexin Li Submitted. 「ArXiv 】
- ▲ Bridging Imitation and Online Reinforcement Learning: An Optimistic Tale Botao Hao, Rahul Jain, Dengwang Tang, Zheng Wen Accepted with minor revision at Transactions on Machine Learning Research. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Sample Efficient Deep Reinforcement Learning via Local Planning Dong Yin, Sridhar Thiagarajan, Nevena Lazic, Nived Rajaraman, Botao Hao, Csaba Szepesvari Submitted to Journal of Machine Learning Research. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Optimization Issues in KL-Constrained Approximate Policy Iteration Nevena Lazic, **Botao Hao**, Yasin Abbasi-Yadkori, Dale Schurmans, Csaba Szepesvári Preprint. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Stochastic Low-rank Tensor Bandits for Multi-dimensional Online Decision Making Jie Zhou, Botao Hao, Zheng Wen, Jingfei Zhang, Will Wei Sun Minor revision at Journal of the American Statistical Association. [ArXiv]
- ▲ Residual Bootstrap Exploration for Bandit Algorithms Chi-Hua Wang*, Yang Yu*, **Botao Hao**, Guang Cheng Preprint. [ArXiv]

HONORS AND AWARDS

- ▲ AISTATS 2022 Top Reviewer
- ▲ NeurIPS 2019 Travel Award
- ▲ Bilsland Dissertation Fellowship 2019-2020

INVITED TALKS

▲ Department of Statistics and Probability, Michigan State University	Oct. 2023
▲ CMStatistics 2022, London, UK	Dec. 2022
▲ RL Forum, Stanford University, CA	Nov. 2022
▲ Deepmind for Google, Mountain View, CA	Jan. 2020
▲ Institute of Statistics, Nankai University, Tianjin	Dec. 2018
▲ International Conference on Data Science, Shanghai	Dec. 2017
▲ The 25th ICSA Applied Statistics Symposium, Chicago	Jun. 2017
▲ Conference on Statistical Learning and Data Science, Chapel Hill, NC	Jun. 2016

SERVICES

- ▲ Session chair for Machine Learning/Intelligence Cluster at 2020 INFORMS annual meeting
- ▲ Co-chair of Ubicomp 2019 Workshop on Continual and Multimodal Learning for Internet of Things, London, UK
- ▲ Reviewers for Journals:

Annals of Statistics

Annals of Applied Probability

Journal of the American Statistical Association Journal of Machine Learning Research Journal of Multivariate Analysis Computational Statistics and Data Analysis The IEEE Control Systems Letters Statistica Sinica Biostatistics

IEEE Transactions on Information Theory

IEEE Journal on Selected Areas in Information Theory

Transactions on Pattern Analysis and Machine Intelligence

Artificial Intelligence

Transactions on Machine Learning Research

▲ Reviewers for Conferences: NeurIPS, ICML, ICLR, AISTATS, AAAI, UAI, SODA